Raghu Varma C

Software Engineer

Frontend Developer having 3+ years of working experience in early stage Startup. I wore many hats in the organization, that allowed room for experience in a wide spectrum of Digital Marketing, Frontend Designing and a Bug Bounty Hunter.

raghuvarma.work@gmail.com

+91 - 6305146372



Hyderabad, India

in linkedin.com/in/raghu-varma-c

WORK EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Linpack Technologies Pvt Ltd.

10/2018 - Present

Hyderabad, India

Start-up

Tasks/Work

- · Writing functional components, react hooks, redux toolkit, npm and JavaScript libraries.
- Handling CRUD Operations.
- Developing features to enhance the user experience.
- · Redesigning website into mobile friendly UI boots customer engagement up to 40% for some of our clients.
- Good practice of web designing, user experience and scalability.
- Working on Digital Marketing involves Google AdWords, Meta Ads, SEO, eCommerce management.

DIGITAL MARKETING Training and Internship

05/2016 - 07/2016

Hyderabad, India.

Tasks/Work

- Search engine optimization and social media marketing.
- Managed to get website rank in Top 5 in google local
- Monitoring google AdWords, analytics and analyzing traffic.
- · Content Writing for various blogs and posts on social media accounts.
- Good Hands on experience in SEO to optimize website and suggesting a developer to make a website mobile friendly.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Technology in IT

ACE Engineering College (Affiliate to JNTUH)

08/2012 - 06/2016

Hyderabad, India.

Course

Information Technology

Intermediate

Delta Juniour College 06/2010 - 04/2012

Hvderabad, India

Course

• Telangana State Board of Intermediate Education.

Maths, Physics & Chemistry.

SKILLS

REACT JS **JAVASCRIP**7 **BOOTSTRAP REST API's** DIGITAL MARKETING **GIT HUB Bug Bounty Hunter**

ACHIEVEMENTS

Internship (05/2016 - 10/2016)

Completed Full-time Internship in digital Marketing from Stallion Technologies Pvt Ltd Hyderabad through Internshala.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Build an app for Wallet to Wallet transfer (11/2016 - 02/2017)

- When Demonetization of banknotes happen in India, most of the people adopted virtual wallet transfers (like Paytm, Mobikwik).
- But most of the wallets missing direct wallet to wallet & transferring back to bank from wallet is challenging, need a minimum balance. The leftover amount cannot transfer to bank.
- So, We build an app to transfer leftover money from one wallet to other so that they can use that amount for like mobile recharging, ordering food.
- We seen a very good response from users, 5k Downloads & worth 3 Lakhs transactions completed in the span of 4 months, but later due to rules and regulations from RBI we stop that service with an idea to build a great product.

ORGANIZATIONS

Youth for Seva (08/2015 - Present)

Full-time volunteer in "YOUTH FOR SEVA" a non-profit social service organization.

LANGUAGES

FNGLISH

HINDI

Professional Working Proficiency

Professional Working Proficiency

TELUGU

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

INTERESTS

MOBILE PHOTOGRAPHY

TRAVELLING

PLAYING CRICKET

READING BOOKS